Eniola Oseni

Lagos, Nigeria | oseni eniola@vahoo.com Linkedln | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Solution-driven Full Stack Developer with 4+ years using a combination of different frameworks technology ranging from Angular, Nodejs, React, and Java Springboot to build user-friendly and mobile responsive software and applications. Proven experience with Software systems development, design, database infrastructure deployment administration, coordinating and pushing new releases to production infrastructure using Amazon Web Services (AWS). Automates and orchestrates application deployment process by building docker images to containerize applications for accessible deployment of on-premises and Cloud infrastructures.

EDUCATION

FEDERAL UNIV. OF ABEOKUTA. OGUN STATE

BSc. Computer Science

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING AND CONCEPTS

- Angular
- ReactJS • Java
- Springboot
 Typescript
- NodeJS ExpressJSHTML5
- SCSS
- BootStrap
 AWS EC2
- AWS S3
- AWS Cloud Formation
- Docker
- Postgres MySQL
- OOP Angular
- JavaScript Wordpress Agile Material
 - Microservices
- Containerization
 Process Automation
- NEWGEN IBPS

TOOLS

• Visual Studio Code • IntelliJ IDEA • MySQL Workbench • pgAdmin • Microsoft Office Suite • Azure Devops • Jira •

SOFT SKILLS

Research and Analysis • Problem Solving • Proposal Development • Written and Verbal Communication • Project Management •Software Developement Life Cycle •Database Technology •Team work & Collaboration

CERTIFICATIONS

- AWS Cloud practitioner (LOTS1LXJHM111YCY) 2021
- NEWGEN TECHICAL CERTIFICATION 1 & 2

EXPERIENCE

WAKANOW | Senior Frontend Engineer

Oct 2022- Present | VI, Lagos State

- Designed and built a user friendly, responsive web application for flights booking, visa application and hotel booking which generated over #20m naira in transaction in the first month of launching.
- Integrated with various 3rd party endpoints,REST APIs and Payment
- Collaborated with technical team to review code base, conduct root cause analysis of issues and identify ideas to enhance system perfomance

ZENITH BANK NIGERIA | Backend Engineer (Contract)

May 2022 - Present | VI, Lagos State

- Modernization and migration of the Corptate Internet Banking application from a monolitic JSP Java enterpised based application to Microservices built using Java Springboot and Angular which improved system performance and application scalability.
- Added new features to the CIB application based on new business requirements. This improved user satisfaction and also increased the number of high volume transactions perfored on the application

UNION SYSTEMS | Senior Software Engineer

Nov 2021 - Sep 2022 | VI, Lagos State

- Worked as a fullstack developer in building an international trade finance web application (KACHASI). which has been deployed to more than 3 different banks in Nigeria. This has helped prevent income leakages in transactions and also improce reconciliation processes
- Developed REST APIs, built analystics dashboard and message and process queuing services to improve application performance and user reports tracking.
- Translate business and functional requirements into tecnical solutions and user interface designs.
- Design and develop software using a variety of languages and technologies to satisfy specified acceptance criteria and stories, ensuring the agile team adhered to development standards.

VERRAKI BUSINESS SOLUTIONS | Software Developer

Aug 2019 - Nov 2021 | VI, Lagos State

- Led the automation and implementation of the TOD (Temporary Overdraft) process at First Bank Plc. successfully utilising NEWGEN IBPS, Java, and JavaScript, which slashed the redundant procedure by 65% and improved processing times for clients and staff by 45%.
- Developed various SaaS web application using modern web frameworks and standard practices. which helped generate revenue for the business and improved turn over and business operations for clients
- Achieved a 99% of web apps by deploying, sustaining and maintining them on AWS cloud

STRAIGHTTALK TECHNOLOGIES | IT Support Trainee

Aug 2019 - Nov 2021 | VI, Lagos State

- Managed corporate site, fixed hardware and software issues aainingnd staff therby enhancing departmental productivity by 25%
- Installation of security software, troubleshooting network issues.